recording over there.  Okay.  And we enter into
processes without services.  Time this
was databases first.
Okay, let's go to processes and services.
Second,
services and processes, which I always
say the other way around.  I always say it backwards
because the subject is called services
and processes,
but then in the syllabus it says
processes first and then services,
right?  But anyway, it doesn't matter, that's the
least of it, obviously.
Okay, so
we stayed last week.  Ah, yes.  Gosh, I don't
know, eh, I have no idea, but I don't
care.  I mean, I also think I have it
wrong with the video schedule,
but I really don't care who
goes first and who goes after.   Just a
moment, because
I have access to data in the course calendar.  Yes,
correct.  So let's go with data access,
okay?  Because I think it comes out backwards.
Yes, yes, it really doesn't matter
, right?  But we're going with
access to data more than anything so that
the recordings are in the
correct order, okay?  I
think the order of
the recordings is incorrect, but
we'll talk about it later, as there's an easy
solution, okay?  So
file management, salization, desalting,
right?  We have already talked about this regarding
connector management.
Okay,
time for file work.
Okay, okay.  To serialize.  And today I want to
talk a little bit about applications that
use files, okay?  Today I want to
talk a little about the object-
relational gap and what it means.
Let's see.  Hey, I'm going to do an
introduction
001 introduction.md MD and I'm going to tell you
the following.
Um, let's
see,
many applications
work
with collections of objects.  Okay, so
now we're going to give an
example.  Obviously, for example, in
Python,
those objects
can have a complex hierarchy
of properties, right?  And that's
it.  And it is like this and it has to be like this
and it is good that it is like this.  Now, I insist,
I will give an example.  The problem is, what
happens when we save
that data?
Solution one, which I think we've
seen these days and yes, I think
we did an exercise, okay?  I'm a
bit mentally unsettled right now, but
solution one, pickle.   Please
confirm whether or not it's true that we saw
a Pickel exercise, but what
Pickel basically does is save all the
information directly into memory, that
is, dump the objects
directly into memory and then
retrieve it.
Pisquel is great, okay?  But Pisquel
is a bit of a beast.  Confirm or not, eh,
if we have done something with Pickel at some
point, because I have it in my
head, but I'm not 100% sure.  Okay,
correct.  I say this because either to avoid
explaining the same thing twice or to avoid
taking for granted what I have
taught you and leaving it unexplained.  Okay?
Solution one, pickle, very beastly, very
cool, but of course, if you then want to
put your hand inside the data,
you realize that you can't put your
hand inside the data.  Okay?  Good.
Solution two,
object relational mapping.
Object-relational mapping
involves transforming data back and forth
to a
relational database.  What does this mean?
Okay, so this means that I
now come here, I'm going to create an
exercise, new file 002 and eh
clients.python.
And here in clients what I'm going to do is
say eh clients equals dictionary
and eh well, client, you know?  Let's
start with the client.  It's equal to
dictionary and then name colon
José Vicente
comma
last name colon.  Carratolá Sánchez
eh email is done.  Well, email, you know
what?  Well, no, eh, emails
and then I open a Ray because I know I
can do it and then I make a
Ray and I say, eh, info@josicente, you
know what?  I open a Ray and I open
objects,
okay?  Because?  because I can.  So
I do this and I say, uh, type a
colon, personal
comma, uh, address, for example,
info@josvicente
cararratalá.com.
Okay, comma because it's a ray,
company
info@jocarsa.com
and I can do whatever I want with
this, that is, I can create as many
arrays of how many objects and here I
can put another array and I know
that with dictionaries and in Python I
can do whatever I want and I know
that if I then save this plain and simple to
a JS, I save it and I'm
happy.  I know that if I then save it to
[ __ ] B, I also know that I'll be
calm because I can do it.  The
problem is when I want to save it in
a relational database,
such as My SQL.  Sure, here
I say, "Okay, I create a table called
customers, but then I create a
column called name, I create a
column called last name."  But of course,
what about emails?  Well, emails is
a Ray, but of course, if it is a Ray, then
I would
say, "Okay, so this looks like
an external table called emails,
an external table with a foreign key,
okay?"  Okay, come on.
But hey, what if I don't have
one personally, but I have addresses?
And in addresses I put a dash,
I put a dash and I put a comma and I put
jocarsa 2@gmail.com.
Damn, we've already messed up, okay?  And
here if you want I'll put a ray too,
more than anything so that the structure is
predictable
because wait, I mean, okay, wait.
So what do I do?  I can put an
array field into Myers SQL, I can
put a JSON field into Myers SQL, I
can, I don't know, right?  Put in a lot
more stuff, but of course, as a
person, as a human being, moreover, if I
format it like this, I understand it
and I say, "Okay, okay, no problem. It's a
client that has several emails and can have several
personal type addresses,
but the moment I start
thinking about how to put this into a
database, well, it blows my mind, okay? It
blows my mind because I say, well, no
problem, there are three tables, you know? It's
a client table and then an
external email table and then,
well, a related external table, I
'm even seeing the SQL schema
in my head of URLs, that is,
email addresses. But
that's not the problem. The problem is
that now I come here
and say telephones
and I have another array and in my head it's
like, [ __ ], again.
Okay, so with the
object-relational mapping, what it's about is
that if I have an application that
handles data and that data, for
business logic needs,
can  be as complex as they need to be
,
how to work in a way that doesn't
break our heads every time we have to
dump. So let's
work with, for example, as I said,
let's work with this example and
see what happens. Besides, I insist,
these are emails, okay? I could make
an array.
I could make a ray,
okay? And obviously
now it would be clients, okay? And I
would have to save this information in
the database. Okay? This is the
mapping, the object-relational offset. I
have an object, a ray of objects with
a predictable structure. Yes,
please. Okay, because the moment
each object has a
different structure, that's when we've really messed up.
But I insist, for an engine
like [ __ ] DB it doesn't matter. It's like,
"Okay, you put it in, you'll sort it out
later."
But with a MySQL-type engine,
well, obviously there are some restrictions,
and to guarantee
relationality, the structure  It has to
be predictable, obviously. Okay,
so let's prepare an insert,
but let's prepare a
dynamic insert in the sense
that
up until now we always created a
structure
in SQL at the beginning and then in
programming we make the program
work with that structure.
But what if when mapping,
at the time of mapping, we
dynamically create the structure, okay? With
what I just told you, I think you'll
see where the exercise is going,
but you'll also see that this is going to be really
cool, okay? So, 003
we extract the structure
of the object.
And then next I say the
following.
Hey, sample equals zero clients,
that is, the first element. Print
sample. Let's see what this gives us. Wait a
minute, because this is from the
previous class, okay? This is email for
later with activity topics.
This is a backup of the SQL that
we were doing before in first.
Let's see. Second, data access,
connector management, offset,
exercises, and terminal.
Okay,
so next I'm going to say Python
3003,
Okay? And we have this over here.
And now next, now
next I say, okay, well tell me
each of the types. Let's see,
we loop through
the object.
Let's see. Oh, careful. We loop through the
object
and I say for key
in, uh, show,
okay? show dot, uh, dict
and
case. I
'm doing this from memory. Okay, wait
a second, maybe it's not correct. Print
key. Let's see because I'm telling you, I'm
doing it from memory. Python 3 004,
right? Uh, show dict case.
No, yes, but wait a second, but
theoretically I think I remember that's
correct, but it seems not,
obviously. Okay, let's see what
I've forgotten.
Let's see.
clients.
Ah, show Kiss. ​​Do you think?
Show KIS. Okay, well, come on, show
KIS. Okay, we
execute. Okay,
first name, last name, emails. Okay, but
next, but next I
say show, that is, print
type of or sorry, type of key. In
Python it is  key, which tells me e
emails. It's a string. Wait. No, no,
sorry, sorry, sorry. No, no, no,
no, no.
Okay, I don't want the key, I want a sample
key.
Okay.
Okay. So, I have class string,
class string, and class list.
So if I have a list there, what's
going to happen is, let's see, I say
if
type
is equal to stras.
Let's see,
in that case, print
is I'm going to convert it
into a column. Let's see it for
a moment, shall we
? Uh,
yeah, but anyway, let's see, I'm going to take this,
but I don't like it very much.
No,
no. Uh, let's see, there's
a detail, it's never fulfilled. It's already
comparing with stream, but I've
compared it and I don't think it ignored me
.
Ah, STR, okay, sorry. str 5 quotes.
That's the problem. Okay.
Okay. This field here, right?
This field name is a Class String and I
'm going to convert it into an
SQL column.
Elif type
shows key
equals list
print. I
'm going to convert it
into an external SQL table, into a
linked external table, okay? An
STR column, of SQL, which will be of type
text
or of type patch. Okay,
there's the problem of the mismatch,
we have to make up for the mismatch with a
mapping. In the same way, the if
type shows equals int, so I'm going
to convert it into an external
MySQL table, sorry, I'm going to convert it into an
SQL column that will be of type into, it
will be of type decimal, okay? Which will be of
type int, which in this case will not be the
if. I
don't recognize the field type or I haven't
been programmed for that type of field.
Attention. Okay, now I insist that if you
're not getting me, tell me, okay?
Because I know what you're going to say, you have an
object, you're looping through the object.
Why are you looping through the object?
Okay, now you'll see.
So next... So
next I go to local host,
I go  In PH, I go to admin, I go to
root,
I go to data access. I already have it from
last year, okay? I'm going to create a
new one called desfase
with UTF8 Spanish.
Desfase.
Privileges. Add user account.
Desfase, desfase, desfase.
Okay, okay. Good. Password.
Okay, desfase. Desfase is empty, so what I'm
going to do next is
connect to MySQL.
Python connect.
Yes, yes. No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no. I'm using my SQL, my
finger slipped.
Okay. Okay. We import
005. We
import MySQL. We
import MySQL. We connect
. We connect
.
We connect to, I don't remember,
desfase,
password desfase, database desfase,
cursor contestor.
Okay. And then
, uh, well, no, cursor execute, no, that
's it, that's correct.
Okay.
Good. And now next, and now next,
what I'm going to do is
create table.
I'm going to do it by hand.
Oh, where are you? Wait.
Offset. Okay, create table. Gee.
Okay, create table. Clients with
four columns.
Incremental primary identifier. It's
always going to be like this,
okay? Uh, first name exactly,
uh, last name exactly,
and email exactly.
Okay, I'll redisplay SQL,
create table. Let's
see if it lets me make
a doc string,
mostly for convenience,
and don't believe it either, but oh well. Okay.
And I execute. Pay attention, look.
Pay attention, look.
Uh, offset is empty. Okay, it's
empty. Now next, I go to
Python 3 003
005.
Okay. Uh, elif.
Oh, gee.
Clear.
Okay. Okay
. It did
n't say anything, which means
now I go to local host, reload
offset, and there's a table called clients
that has this structure.
So, so,  What do you think
if I now say the following?
006 I create a list of fields.
And I say,
fields equals list.
Please, if you see where I'm going,
say, let's see where you're going. And if you don't
see where I'm going, tell me in the
chat, I don't know where this leads.
Maybe you see where I'm going and say,
"Okay, we'll see where you're going and you're
crazy." Okay, I don't know, you guys tell me
because this exercise is very abstract.
Okay? Then I say, uh, OK, campus,
campus, okay? With which, with which I
come over here and say fields punapen
fields. Apen key
and that's it. Okay,
no, Fran. Exactly. Literally what I
'm doing is an ORM,
but a dynamic ORM.
Entering data, right? Now without using PHP My
admin, that's a little bit more indifferent to me,
okay? But entering data by creating like in
an ORM, unlike a URM, the issue
with the ORM is that a pure ORM is that a
person has to program the  mapping
and that can sometimes be suicide.
Our goal, mental suicide. I
mean, the goal, our
goal is to parse an object, now
you'll see recursively,
so that the program itself
does the mapping. Okay? Let's go for
it. Now you'll see.
So campus appen. Key, so
I'm going to create table
and I'm going to do the following. I see here,
we're going to separate this. I see here, I see here
, I see here, I see here. Okay, what
things do I know? Well, I know primary key,
okay? Okay. Come on, I know that I'm
always going to have the identifier,
so I say string is equal to
this
and then at the end I'll put string.
By the way, in the execute I'm going to say
drop table clients, okay? To then
create it.
Drop table clients.
Okay,
now next. Now next
I say here
triki triqui tricky, okay? And I say for
field in fields
string plus equals triki triki triki
and triki triki triki and then
string string plus equals triqui  Triiki triqui.
Okay, if this is true before
executing anything, if you want before
executing anything we'll see it on the screen.
print string
and pay attention if I now execute and this
we're in 6
create table offset identifier first
name last name wait what's happening here
sorry sorry sorry eh string okay it's
triki triki triki more triki triki triki
and I'm missing one more
field okay.
Create first name, last name.
Last name again. Ah, wait, sorry.
Here.
Okay,
now yes. First name, last name and for the moment it
's skipping the phone numbers, okay? Or
the emails, whatever. Now we'll see.
But if I now, but if I now say,
no, wait, it's because I have another field
which is DNI,
okay? DNI,
of course, let there be some uniformity
because otherwise it will be chaos, okay? DNI,
well now I execute again and in the
SQL query, I don't know if you see it, but
DNI appears,
which means that now I do run
the query to the database  of data. 007. I
launch the query to the database.
Okay. And I execute a Oh, I can. I execute a
drop, I
execute a chain. I
execute 007,
I go to My SQL, I
recharge
eh of phase, I recharge clients and clients
now have DNI,
that is, you realize that the
update is automatic. Okay, but
but now I insist, I'm only creating
the structure. No, no, no, no, no, no. I
can only enter barchar. I mean, I've
created barchar, I've
created barchar, no, no, of the same
type, no, no, no, because here remember
that I'm saying, if it's a
varchar type string, but what if it's an
integer type field, well I'm going to enter it as
integer type. I mean, let's see it.
Okay, key type fields.
So now over here, okay? I'm going to
say, I'm going to say em up here,
look, I'm going to put age.
Correct, correct, correct. Let's
see it. Let's  prove it. Age
equals 47 comma, okay? An integer and age
have to be in the same structure,
okay? It's equal to 45, an integer,
okay? And so now here I'm going to
do it a little bit extravagantly. If eh field type
is str in that case,
trucunchu
elif
field type
is int.
In that case I'm going to do trucu trunchu,
but but let's see.
Come on, let's go there, Luis. Let's go
there. Just a moment, just a moment. I see this
exercise, look,
ah, I see what you're
saying backwards, but I think it's related
to what you're saying. I mean, eh,
this exercise is designed so that
someone enters a piece of data of
whatever complexity and that someone knows that when they hit
send that it's going to enter the
database without that someone having to
worry about whether the complexity of that
data matches or not with MySQL,
because it will already adapt to MySQL, okay? Not
so much designed for an end user,
but so that a programmer has a
object and can give the object the
complexity that it wants and know
that then calm because that will
enter the database. It will enter,
by the way, and it will also return. Now
we will talk about that, okay? So,
now here I say int 255, for example.
Okay, so if this is true,
if this is true, then
now I execute, well, I think I
'm in the same 007,
okay? Okay. I'm going to the database. A
moment ago the Ah, no, age didn't exist
. Okay, I'm going to lag, I'm going
here, I'm not going to structure because I'm not
seeing. Ah, here clients, sorry.
Here I'm going to structure and wait,
wait, wait, because it didn't
get me. It didn't get me. Okay.
Age.
Field type, field type, field type.
No, no, no, no. Sure, sure, sure. No,
sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry. Sure, sure
, clear. No, I would have to
put in a dictionary. I would have to put in
a  Dictionary. I mean, yes, it can be
done, right? I'm not doing it
correctly because, of course, field takes
the field name, and the
field name is a string. Instead of passing a
list, I would have to pass a dictionary
where the dictionary would include the
field name and the data type.
Okay, but okay. Okay, then wait a
second because this, I mean, this
specific point isn't well-posed, okay?
But I used to pass a dictionary, okay?
And now, and now what I want to
worry about right now, apart from the fact that
you've seen that I'm expanding the
data model and it automatically
appears in SQL,
but now for me the scary thing is what's
going to happen in emails. Okay?
So, in emails, I'm going to remove
this for a moment.
Let's see. Uh, address.
Address. I'm going to remove this for a moment,
I insist, to start little by little,
because otherwise the blow is going to be maximum.
Okay, same here.
Okay, so now for this part of the
exercise, I'm going to rely on chat.
GPT.
This is a 008 table
referenced
with a foreign key, okay? And
let's see, uh, modify
so that uh this is an array.
Okay. Okay.
So that
array properties
are created
as a foreign
key
external.
table in my SQL, okay? And that's it.
So, now basically what
the logic is going to do is say, well, if it
's a string, we're going to enter it as
create table, but if it's a list,
in that case it's no longer a campus. Appen,
in that case, create a table, create
another table and link the tables. Okay,
let's see it.
And then finally, in quotes, in
the exercise, we're doing the
outward journey, okay? Which is saving. Then we have to
do the return journey,
which is collecting. Okay? So, okay
. Okay
. Okay. Uh, and but. Please make it
work. Not only for this case emails
but for any abstract case.
Okay, I mean, I'm looking at the code and it
's preparing the logic for the
emails, okay?  Normalize emails. I don't
have an email problem, okay? What
Uh, wait.
No, but hey, wait, wait. No,
I do
n't have an address. Ah, no, no, no, sorry,
sorry, sorry, sorry. No, no, no.
Damn, stop it
then. Ah, uh, no, no, sorry, uh, I have
simplified
a bit of code. New code.
New code is this.
Let's see.
I say this because the code I had,
the dictionary I had, is like two
or three steps further. Okay, I prefer to
do it little by little, okay?
First an object within an object and
then we pass it an array within
an array within an array and then what I'll
tell it is make it recursive. Okay? I
mean, make it recursive in the
sense that we don't know how
deep the array or the
object is going to be, but we don't care because since you're
going to make it recursive, it simply
parses the object one by one. Okay. Good.
Regular expression.  No, this isn't what
I wanted, but okay. Okay.
Damn, addresses. Ah, [ __ ],
addresses. Okay, okay
.
Okay. What's going on? Well, with this
logic,
let's see, this is a referenced table,
okay? With this logic, what it's
doing is, on the one hand, creating tables,
okay? Drop tables first and then
creating tables. Wait, where are they?
Here. And it creates the constraints, okay? And it
automatically creates the necessary constructs
so that everything stays linked
together. So, now confirmation,
Python
3.008,
okay? And then, notice
I have root, daughter, and granddaughter.
And now I go to MySQL,
I go to offset,
and I have clients, email clients, and
email clients, addresses. Okay,
I have the client, although I've
duplicated it, but oh well. I have José
Vicente Caratelá Sanchez. I have José
Vicente Carratela.
Oh, okay, sorry, it creates the
structure for me, but not the Okay, not the
data, it's no problem. Okay.  Okay. Okay,
perfect.
Hm. Okay. Perfect. Awesome.
And now please also insert
data.
Okay, now this is the structure, and
now we'll also insert the data.
Okay? The concept, ultimately, isn't
just that it exists.
ORM, but the objective in this
second unit that we started today with
object-relational debase is to create
our own connectors. That is,
the pure management of connectors at the
user level, we already covered that in the first one. That
is, you have a connector, you connect, you
pass parameters, you have connected, you
receive data, and enjoy life.
The objective in data access is
for us to create those connectors,
okay? And ultimately, to create
customized solutions to any
problem that may exist. I say this
because in the coming days, as you can see
here, database access protocols
, establishing connections,
this isn't about connecting to MySQL, we've
known that since the first month of the
first year. That's about creating
a database connector ourselves or creating
a database ourselves, okay? Creating
a customized
data access solution ourselves.
Okay? So I come over here,
I run 009,
okay? And the last batch may not
reflect the total, it's okay. Okay,
I come over here, I go to offset, I
go to clients. Just a moment to
update,
I go to clients and I have two clients
that are the same. Okay, now, now one
of them I go to clients emails and I
have personal and company, which in this
case there are none, and I have clients,
emails, addresses and I have the
addresses. Okay, but now, but
now next
I'll tell you, and this is the final step of the
first part of this exercise.
Please make it recursive
to work
with any possible uh to
any with any possible
data structure
J son dict uh list okay so without
going crazy obviously
and please load data from external
JSON. And while it's doing this, what I
'm going to do is I'm going to create a
new file called datos.json.
Inside datos.json so as not to mix up the
code within Python, okay? What I
'm going to do is create a JSON. I'm going to
go to  I'm going to go to the chat
and I'm going to say, uh,
create a JSON with an array of
clients with an indeterminate number
of
data depths, but it has to be consistent
between the elements of the Ray because otherwise there's
no business.
Okay? So, in other words, the chat is going to
generate a JSON that I don't control,
okay? Because the objective is to demonstrate
if this structure can be used with
any JSON, okay? Well,
mobile-type phone numbers, address, okay? And
address is a different story. History,
purchases, okay? And okay. And now another
client. Email, phone numbers, address,
history, purchases. Okay, fantastic, I
love it. So I copy,
data Jon, paste it, and I have a JSON with
a structure that I didn't create, but I
start reading it and say, "Okay,
clients, okay, it's a Ray, okay?" Okay,
so ID, name, information,
contact, email, phone numbers, type, but
history, purchases, purchase,
products.  Sure, I see the JSON and as a
person and as a programmer I say, "Okay,
okay, it's all there, it seems
clear, it's well structured, it's cool, it makes
sense, but eh, but this is going to
be a huge blow, okay? I mean, I have to
put it into SQL myself, I'm going to
spend three days racking my brains. Wait
a minute, because originally my
logic had a Ray to start with.
Okay, but oh well, it's not a problem. Now we'll
see. Hey, let's see. It might not work
at first. It
might not work at first. Okay. And
eh, we put this in here. 010 recursive.
Okay. And I'm going to say I'm going to say I'm going to
say before it blows up because it's going to
blow up. Okay. Hey, sorry. It should work
with this kind of logic. Hey, root elements being eh parent top level
parent tables.
Oh, [ __ ], [ __ ], [ __ ], [ __ ],
[ __ ]. No, eh, with here, here.
That makes me really mad when I hit
enter and I think GP is going to  say,
"I don't understand what you know.
Let's see.
Okay,
let's see.
Okay.  Oh, okay.  Okay.
And and copy and recursive.  Okay,
this is recursive.  Okay, let's go.  And it's JSON data.
Let's see it.
Python 3 eh 0 10.
Okay.  Okay.  Let's see.  Can of drop
table clients.  Okay.  Mr.
Vale.  Hey, I'll ask.  Could
it be done?
a full
drop of all existing tables without
eh FK
or
restriction or constraints
checking, okay?  something really
big, I mean, something like, "Get rid of
everything",
and then, obviously if we put this
software into production, it would be a
bit of a wait before getting rid of
things, think about it, I mean,
but
okay, just
a moment.
Come on, as I said, make sure
we make the outward journey, and once
we make the outward journey, from
there making the return journey
will be easy.  That is, the way
back will be to take the My
SQL database, recover it and convert it to a
mega object in Python or
whatever language, obviously.
Okay, so let's see.
Okay.  Yes, please.  Hey, full code on
script start.
Please drop everything.
existing
on database and create new structure.
Okay, I'm telling you that what I'm
doing is very
brutal, that is, what I'm doing
are two operations.  First, create the
structure and second, enter the data.
Okay,
in a more advanced version, which is not
today yet, because oh, how angry it makes me
that Oh.
Look, I don't want to put
CLI parameters on it, what I want is,
okay, well, in a more advanced way
of, look, the structure matches my
JSON, don't destroy it, okay?  Use it.
Now, it doesn't match my JSON or the
database is empty, please create it.  It doesn't match
my JSON, please ask me.  Okay, let's
see this over here,
this over here.  But today is above all
a demonstration.
Okay.  Okay.  You see?  The following.  It
makes me so angry.  Please,
without CLI,
everything
in the code.  Okay, because lately I don't
know why, even if I don't ask it, it
always makes programs with
Commandline CLI parameters and it's like,
wow, right?  I mean, but well, I mean,
I understand that from a programming point of view it
's better and that it's
making me a script that I could then
execute and customize.  and I could
reuse it for the Command Line
Interface, I mean, I understand that it
does it well and that it has its advantages,
but damn it's like that, but I don't
want it.  Let's see.
Okay.
Let's see,
let's do a full
au
information of Oh, okay, okay, okay,
okay.  It's to long.
Come on.
Okay, I don't know, I don't know how to solve this error
because of course, if it tells me that the
problem is that the name of the
column or table identifier in
My SQL is too long, well, maybe it
starts making prefixes, I don't know.
Okay, 64 characters,
okay?  Automatically shorten with a
hash.  [ __ ],
wait.
Well, let's see if it works, we'll
think about how to change the
solution later.  Well, if you do a hash, the
problem is that it's going to work,
but it's going to be pretty impossible for me to
figure out what each thing is in
the database.
And obviously if in the end we have something
similar to Pckel where I can look but I ca
n't understand anything, then we'll
be left the same.  But anyway, let's
see if what I want is to
see if this first part already works and I
can show it to you in operation
to tell you, look, the JSON Patap has been
inserted directly with all the tables
that were necessary within the
database.
And obviously, beyond
using an existing ORM connector,
what we're doing, as you can
see, is creating our own
ORM connector.
Let's see.
Okay, let's see.
Okay, let's see if we've had any
luck.  Okay, we're going here, we're going
to local host, we're going to offset,
okay?  For now, I see things I
like, and then I see clients. I see
Vicente Cáratalá and Ana López. I see
purchase history. I see client
purchase history, products. I see
client contact information.  That
is, you are seeing how the system,
starting from a JSON of
unknown hierarchical complexity,
recursively
parses the logic and converts it into a
relational model
where at a given moment, unlike
a pickle, I can enter here and I
can see things and I can manipulate things.
Okay, and I can do searches and I can
benefit, obviously, from the benefits of
the relational model.  Very good.  But
now next, now next
I want the opposite, okay?
Now, now I would like.
That's the point, right?  Agustín and it's
you, imagine that it changes, I mean, right now
just as it's programmed, okay?
Keeping in mind that it
does a massive database crash
, right now every time I
run it, it's going to load the database
and put in whatever data is there,
okay?  So right now the
answer is yes, but because I've
forced the drop like crazy.  The question
I would ask you back, the question I
would bounce back to you is, what should happen?
That is, if I already have the
database created and I receive a JSON that
has a slightly
different structure, what should happen?   It
depends, okay?  Depending on the company
we are in, one thing
or another can happen.  So, the company might
say, hey, it's not that if they give you a
new one, it's that you should get rid of the old one,
this new one is the one that counts.  Or maybe the
company says, "No, if you pass a
new one, parse it, make an alter table to
adapt to the new structure and then
enter the data."  But that's the
point, that's what this
exercise is about.  The thing is, if you use a
pre-built URM controller, whatever
the controller does is up to you
.  But if you make a
controller, you control what
the controller does and you can adapt
to what the client needs to do.  And that's
what this subject is about, okay?  As for
you, tell me what you need to
save, don't worry, I'll save it for you,
okay?  That's a bit of what it's
about.
And well and well and well now I would like.  And
now you'll see how this ends.  Another
different script.
to make the opposite to
pars to par no to
enter database
get all the information
and recover it as Python
dictionary oo
yes it goes it goes it goes Python dictionary
And
to receive it one aspectary
two and save
to jon that is to say the inverse way because you
say okay we have it is like unmounting the the
read
the j entered in the database but
for that we have had to unmount it
with which we see it in SQL but now it
is like, "Okay, and where is my
Jason S now?"  Well, it's
scattered around in SQL.  Okay, so now
I want the opposite.  Now I want another
script that goes into
the database, starts building
relationships, and returns a JSON to me.  And
theoretically
the final JSON should be the same as the
initial JSON.  And if you don't see it, then
we have a problem, okay?  And
then, without CLI, okay?  And
then, as you can imagine,
this exercise will end with making a
connector.  That is, now create a
class.  The class will have two methods.
Method one will be writing, method two
will be reading, with which we will have created
a constructor preview, sorry, a
connector preview that we can use
in any program, right?  Very
prototyped today, obviously, but
you get the idea, right?
Because apart from this local hostase, it
would have to be a
configuration file or a JS or a dot M, I don't
know, okay?  Or tell me your
database details and I'll adapt your
database, I don't know.  That is, today it is
forced to lag.
Okay, so, then, okay, I copy
code.
Okay, now this is going to be
011 lectorpython.
Okay.  Okay.  And D recovered.  Perfect.  I
like it.  Okay, so I now
next say Python 3 011 reader.
Okay.  And this is the JSON data
and this is the retrieved dam.
And I don't know about you, but except for some
character, ah, no, inch, okay, it's that he
put an escape character, okay?
except for some character that I see around that
is an escape character.  I don't know about
you, but I think it's [ __ ] great,
because with this I know that if I have an
object and that object has a
high complexity, but at the same time I want to
take advantage of the benefits of SQL, I know that
I'm going to be able to use it, I know that I'm going to be
able to do it, okay?  And I know that my
program can work with any set
of objects I want, and then I
'll be able to persist it in SQL, so that it
stays saved in SQL, so that it stays
stored.  If I want to do
SQL searches, I'll be able to do them, and if at some
point I need to retrieve it as an
object, I'll be able to retrieve it, okay?
And nothing happens.  Well, that's okay,
okay?  Yes, it does happen
because in the end, whether you like it or not, I'm never going to
say at any point that SQL
is dying, but in the end, with
the years that you know about it, we won't do it anymore.   We're
doing this today because
SQL databases are still
very important and will
continue to be so for at least the
next 10 years.
In a few years, what we will do is
directly use [ __ ] Deb or similar.   That
is, why do I want to
save it in SQL?  I save it in a non-SQL and that's it,
and I avoid the hassle of
doing ORM.  Okay, but okay, but it's not
the day yet, okay?  So uh
now next, now
next.
Okay, I like it so much.
Now
let's create a class
that implements
both ways
as methods.
create the class
and after that create demo
code
to read and write that is use both
methods
and now is when I start to
package it okay now is when I say,
"Okay, one script works,
another one works, well now I would like to have it in
a connector. Now I would like to
design a connector with it, okay? Ch
GPT who has already seen my idea, says,
"Awesome, okay?  Because he says, okay, you
see what you want.  What you want is to
program a connector and now
you'll see that we're going to use
the connector transparently
through an import, okay?  So a
single class that implements both
paths and then, okay?  From
here JS My SQL Bridge, okay?   just
a moment.
And now, Luis,
this is where we're going to get to what you were saying.
Okay,
now I'm going to show you how
the end user would use it.  The thing is, the
end user isn't, I'm not seeing
the same thing as you, that is, it's not the
non-expert end user, but I
'm seeing this to give it to a
programmer and say, take it.
Hey, take a JSON, put it into MySQL, and
the programmer says, "Wow, how do you
do that?"  And you tell him,
"Calm down, the class will do it, okay? Do
n't worry, don't worry,
Jason will go and come back. Then, and
then obviously, if he wants to know
more, he can come into the class to
find out."  Clear.
Okay.  So, I do this.  You're seeing
how the class, of course, that you tell him
is 50 € obviously, right?  Or that or that
you say to him, "What if you liked it, will you
hire me? You know? I mean, or something like that
or that I wish it, although this is difficult to
offer as a service because since it is a
software, let's say, Python, another thing is
that instead of doing it with Python, we
do it with a language that we can
compile like C++ and you give him the
executable and then you say, "It's
€50", you know? and what if he says, "No,
but I want the source code." And you
say, "If you want the source code,
hire me and I'll bring the source code into
the company." But you know, but anyway,
that's how each one of you
obviously manages the issue.
Let's see. Wait, we're still on
it.
Okay, now for the demo. Very good, perfect.
Ah, look, he's taken my
connection data out, which was to be
expected. Very good. Okay
. Okay. Good. I don't care a little more about this.
This is  a print, but oh well.
Okay.
Okay. Fantastic. Copy code. Okay,
so 012 class demo. Python
okay the file is big,
okay? and I run it. Okay, first
write and then read. It's data J are and
where and Adom retrieved. Okay,
fantastic. Well, uh Python 3
and 012 and demo. Okay, fantastic.
Clients, two elements, everything works the
same. Okay, fantastic. But of course,
now this exercise ends.
The last step of this exercise is
when I call this JV ORM, okay? Which is
going to be no, it's going to be
no, because obviously I should have
called the class like that, but I don't care
. JVORM
and in JVORM,
JVORM
what I do
is I do like this,
okay? And now in class demo I
save it as 013 use of the class.
I load all this and this exercise
ends up
doing the following.
Python, I mean Python chat GPT is very
clean and it's very cool and it makes the
main method for Python and all that. It's highly
recommended,  Obviously, but I don't
want to. I want to make it as simple as
possible.
So I say
from JVORM
import
jQuery bridge
bridge equals local host offset
offset whatever you want and now
write these are comment lines
that are obviously cool. Okay, and
that's it. And this, Luis, is what I was telling you
before. For me, my perspective of this
exercise, this is what the
user who uses this library is going to see. That's why I
tell you that I see it more as a
programmer than an end user. And
now I execute.
And the fact of having encapsulated everything, well, it
serves us for 013 and that's it,
okay? And there we have it. It's obviously caused a
cache hit, having
extracted this to an external file,
but hey, no problem, it
precompiles it and that's it. Okay,
this is the objective of today's class,
to show you that this concept exists and that
we can intervene in this concept to
customize how this ORM is made. In
future classes of this
subject, what we will do,  Take my
words with a grain of salt, okay?
It's about programming a MySQL,
making it clear that obviously within the
scope of the class we won't have
time, okay?, to program a
complete MySQL,
but at least if the
database subject is about using
databases, that is, using
database connectors, how does that work
internally? Ah, mystery, you use it and that's it
. Okay, this data access subject
, this second point of managing
connectors is creating a connector. You can
create a connector, okay? You can
even create your own database system,
being realistic. I mean,
we'll do something that will give you a sample that you
can do it and then,
obviously, doing something the size of
MySQL, well, that means spending hours and hours
and hours and millions of hours and having
more people and all that. Okay? Okay, very
well. So let's continue. M.